I've decided to start a YouTube
channel.
The West is leading
Ukraine down the primrose path
The Israelis
are executing a genocide in Gaza.
It's not China's fault
that it wants to be powerful.
So if you get into trouble
and you dial 911,
there's nobody at the other end.
Hi, I'm John Mearsheimer and I've decided
to start a YouTube channel.
I think this will be
an excellent opportunity for me
to expand on different issues,
which I talk about on
the various shows that I do,
and also give me an opportunity
to talk about topics
that I don't address in those shows,
which I think
that you might find interesting.
To give you a good sense
of what I have in mind.
Let me talk about a number of different
categories of topics
that I plan to address
in these forthcoming videos.
First of all, I'd like to talk about
contemporary political issues
such as the war in the Middle East.
And here we're talking about the Iran War,
of course.
And I'd like to talk about why that war
started,
how it's been conducted,
and where the war is headed.
And furthermore,
I'd like to talk about the Ukraine war,
and to give you a sense
of what I'd like to do there.
I'm very interested in the whole question
of how that war
started back in February of 2022.
And when I was a graduate student,
I wrote a PhD dissertation
on conventional deterrence,
which actually became my first book.
And I think that that book on conventional
deterrence has a lot to say
about the origins of the Ukraine war,
and I'd like to address that subject.
Furthermore, I'd like to talk about
important historical issues.
For example, last month, last June 22nd,
was the anniversary of the German invasion
of the Soviet Union,
the infamous Operation Barbarossa in 1941,
which I think
was one of the most important
historical events of all time.
I'd like to devote an entire show
to talking about
that military campaign.
Furthermore,
I'd like to talk about the workings
of the international system,
how I think international politics works.
To put it in slightly
different terms, I'd like to talk
about international relations theory.
As you know,
there's a lot of interest these days.
For example,
in the state of the international order.
What does the international order
look like today?
What has happened
to the liberal international order?
What is the future
of the international order?
These are all big topics and topics
that I've spent a lot of time
thinking about, and I'd like to address
in a subsequent video.
Furthermore,
I'd like to talk about books and articles
that I think
people might find interesting.
And these, of course, would be books
that I judged to be important.
A good example would be a new book
that's coming out called Israel's Lobby
by Eli Clifton and Ian Lustick.
This is a fascinating book that deals
with the subject,
which, as you know, is dear to my heart.
That is the Israel lobby.
And I'd like to talk at some length
about that book and talk about
how it compares to the book that Steve,
Walt and I wrote back in 2007.
And then finally, I take trips
from time to time to various places
around the world, and sometimes I learn
very interesting things on those trips.
And when I do, what I'd like to do
is come back and talk to you
about my findings,
and hopefully you would find
that interesting,
all of the videos that I present
on this YouTube channel
to be of great interest.
With that thought in mind,
I would encourage all of you
to subscribe to my YouTube channel
and I will do my best to produce
first rate videos for you.
Thank you very much.